Guide to the Ivory Coast (Côte d'Ivoire) Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Ivory Coast (Côte d'Ivoire) collection
1960-2013
MS 1522
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.52
(7 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to the history, geography, and politics of the Ivory Coast. Also included are photographs and slides.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection, MS 605; African Postcard Collection, MS 1575; Pamphlet Collection, MS 1351. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the original accession is arranged chronologically, with photographs last. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to the history, geography, and politics of the Ivory Coast. Also included are photographs and slides.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Côte d'Ivoire -- Description and travel; Côte d'Ivoire -- Politics and government; Photographs -- Côte d'Ivoire
- Original Accession, 1960-1990
  - General information pamphlets; brochures; booklets, 1960-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Government documents; journals; reports, 1972-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Periodicals, 1975-1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Political organizations: documents; journals; printed material, 1980-1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs: newsletters, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Souvenirs des Jeux D'Abidjan": photographs, 1961 December 24-31 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
- Additional Material, 1980-1997; Accession 1995-M-173
  - Additional printed materials, 1982-1996, undated (Box 1)
  - Additional printed materials, [1980?], 1996, 1997 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, 1996-1997; Accession 2000-M-021
  - Almanach du Centenaire, 1893 à nos jours, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Expo Côte d'Ivoire 96: Catalogue Officiel, 1996 (Box 1)
  - SATMACI (Ministère de l'Agriculture), Undated (Box 1)
- Additional Material, 1962-1999; Accession 2006-M-041
  - "Bulletin Terre Humaine 8", 1984 April (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Côte d'Ivoire Actualités," Revue mensuelle, nos. 1-12 [binder of color slides with text], 1976 January-December (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ethnies d'Afrique - La Côte d'Ivoire, Les Expressions du PARLE (Programme Africane pour Réunification Linguistique des Ethnies), NEI (Nouvelles Éditions Ivoiriennes), no. 1, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fraternité, no. 192, 1962 December 28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Ivory Coast, bi-weekly publication of Ivory Coast Ministry of Information, no. 57, 1968 April 25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Notre Police: Organe Officiel du Ministère de la Sécurité Intérieure, " no. 7, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - République de Côte d'Ivoire, "Revue de la Gendarmerie Nationale," no. 24, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Vaillante Afrique: Bulletin des Responsables du Mouvement C.V.-A.V. de Cote d'Ivoire," no. 3, 1984 March (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Yan Kadi: Journal Mensuel du Bureau National d'Etudes Techniques de Developpement," no. 8, 1974 October (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Additional Material, 1982-1996; Accession 2010-M-098
  - Bol Kotch: hebdomadaire satirique ivorien, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Côte d'Ivoire (enquete Ivoirienne sur les migrations et urbanisation), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Agripromo, 1992, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Additional material, 1964-2000s; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 1964-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Posters, Circa 2000s (Box 2, Folder 1)